Guide to the American Baptist Foreign Mission Society records, 1813-1961
American Baptist Foreign Mission Society records, 1813-1961
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
American Baptist Foreign Mission Society Records, 1813-1961
4424
American Baptist Foreign Mission Society
62 reels microfilm
Microfilms of correspondence and files.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Missionary correspondence (1817-1900) and geographic files relating to activities of the American Baptist Foreign Mission Society in Burma.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Missionary correspondence (1817-1900) and geographic files relating to activities of the American Baptist Foreign Mission Society in Burma.
SUBJECTS
Names:
American Baptist Foreign Mission Society.
Subjects:
Baptists--Missions--Burma.; Missionaries--Burma.; Missions, American--Burma.
Places:
Burma--Description and travel.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Available Copies:
Originals at American Baptist Historical Society, 3001 Mercer University Drive, Atlanta, GA 30341.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Missionary correspondence, 1829-1900
Reels FM-1 - FM-115
Series II. Subject file--Burma
Reels 700-1-1 - 712-1-3
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Missionary correspondence, 1829-1900
  - E.L. Abbott, 1836-1854 Rosa H. Adams, 1868-1872 Thomas Allen, 1853-1856. (Reel FM-1)
  - Thomas Allen, 1857-1859 Emma Ambrose, 1881-1892. (Reel FM-2)
  - Cephas Bennett, 1834-1884. (Reel FM-3)
  - J. G. Binney, 1844-1884 Moses Bixby, 1851-1863 (Reel FM-4)
  - Moses Bixby, 1864-1871 Lillian Black, 1894-1895 George Boardman letters, 1823-1830 Mrs. George Boardman, 1831-1829, journals, 1821-1828 (Reel FM-5)
  - George Boardman journals, 1829-1831 Rev. & Mrs. George Boardman personal letters to relatives and friends, various dates D.L. Brayton, 1838-1890 Julia Bromley, 1878-1881 Nathan Brown, 1833-1835 J.L. Bulkely, 1892-1898 Edwin Bullard, 1844-1847 A. Bunker, 1866-1869. (Reel FM-6)
  - A. Bunker, 1870-1899 Zillah Bunn, 1882-1896 T.H. Burhoe, 1893-1896 Walter Bushell, 1878-1884. (Reel FM-7)
  - Walter Bushell, 1892-1900, William Calder, 1888-1898 H.M. Campbell, 1850-1853 C.H. Carpenter, 1862-1880. (Reel FM-8)
  - C.H. Carpenter, 1881-1886 A.E. Carson, 1887-1900 J.E. Case, 1882-1900 John Chandler, 1840-1843 H.P. Cochrane, 1892-1900 W.W. Cochrane, 1890-1900 I.D. Colburn, 1864-1880 G.S. Comstock, 1834-1836. (Reel FM-9)
  - G.S. Comstock, 1837-1844 Elton S. Corson, 1897-1900 Marie Cote, 1894-1900 A.A.R. Crawley, 1853-1895 F.D. Crawley, 1895-1900 L.W. Cronkhite, 1881-1900 Benjamin Cross, 1872-1900. (Reel FM-10)
  - E.B. Cross, 1845-1873 (Reel FM-11)
  - E.B. Cross, 1874-1884, 1892-1900 Ulee Cross, 1878 A.V.B. Crumb, 1876-1900 J.E. Cummings, 1892-1900 Sarah Cummings, 1832-1834 (Reel FM-12)
  - J.N. Cushing, 1867-1890 (Reel FM-13)
  - J.N. Cushing, 1891-1899, sermons Oliver Cutter, 1832-1835, journals C.L. Davenport, 1895-1900 John Dawson, 1849-1852 (Reel FM-14)
  - John Dawson, 1853-1862 L.J. Denchfield, 1884-1896 John Douglass, 1851-1873 Lydia Dyer, 1894-1898 Harriet Eastmen, 1873-1899 Albert Ehrgott, 1900 J.T. Elwell, 1879-1900 Alexander Estabrooks, 1875-1879 Kate Evans, 1871-1897 F.H. Eveleth, 1873-1900 Ellen Fay, 1892 R. Henry Ferguson, 1889 M.E. Fletcher, 1893-1895. (Reel FM-15)
  - M.E. Fletcher, 1896-1900 Anna Frederickson, 1893 Jacob Freiday, 1877-1886 Asenath Gage, 1867-1877 Ann Gardner, 1835-1836 Naomi Garton, 1882-1896 George Geis, 1892-1900 William George, 1869-1896 David Gilmore, 1890-1899 S.T. Goodell, 1871-1878 W.F. Gray, 1897-1900. (Reel FM-16)
  - Ernest Grigg, 1891-1899 William Griggs, 1890-1900 Henry Hale, 1874-1899 Levi Hall, 1837 Royal Hancock, 1832-1841, 1866-1872 (Reel FM-17)
  - Royal Hancock, 1880-1900 Ola Hanson, 1891-1900 Robert Harper, 1898-1900 Amy Harris, 1895 E.N. Harris, 1847-1900 W.H.S. Hascall, 1874-1900 James Haswell, 1863-1854 (Reel FM-18)
  - James Haswell, 1855-1883 James R. Haswell, 1860s-1877 S.E. Haswell, 1868-1876, 1881-1900 Hattie Hawks, 1889-1892 Albert Haws, 1863-1866 A.H. Henderson, 1893-1900 (Reel FM-19)
  - Charles Heptonstall, 1897-1900 Charles Hibbard, 1853-1866 L.E. Hicks, 1894-1900 Sarah Higby, 1876-1900 Annie Hopkins, 1893-1895 Henry Hopkinson, 1871-1876 George Hough, 1817-1828 Hosea Howard, 1836-1859 Lovell Ingalls, 1835-1854. (Reel FM-20)
  - Lovell Ingalls, 1855-1856 Mrs. Lovell Ingalls, 1857-1884, 1892-1900 Melvin Jameson, 1870-1879. (Reel FM-21)
  - Melvin Jameson, 1880-1900 Truman Johnson, 1894-1900 John Jones, 1830-1832, journals ? 1831 E.D. Kelley, 1872-1889 E.W. Kelley, 1882-1900 Eugenio Kincaid, 1830-1856 (Reel FM-22)
  - Eugenio Kincaid, 1857-1847 M.B. Kirkpatrick, 1888-1900 K.E. Knapp, 1850-1862 Kate Knoght, 1895-1898 Julia Lathrop, 1844-1855 Elizabeth Lawrence, 1895 George Leeds, 1897-1900 Lydia Lillybridge, 1847-1850 Mrs. J.J. Longley, 1876-1881 A.J. Lyon, 1877-1878 Eleanor MacComber, 1837-1839 W.R. Manley, 1880 Miss M.S. Manning, 1875-1877. (Reel FM-23)
  - Francis Mason, 1830-1854. (Reel FM-24)
  - Francis Mason, 1855-1863. (Reel FM-25)
  - Francis Mason, 1864-1879 Mrs. Francis Mason, 1880-1882 Sarah Mason, 1860 Ella McAllister, 1878-1900 Selden McCurdy, 1899-1900 John McGuire, 1892-1900 E.J. Miller, 1890-1896 Miss L. E. Miller, 1878-1888 Ella Mitchell, 1880-1895 B.J. Mix, 1880-1899. (Reel FM-26)
  - Annie Modisett, 1893-1894 Clavin Moore, 1849-1855 William Moore, 1848-1855 H. Morrow, 1877-1900 L.H. Mosier, 1890-1900. (Reel FM-27)
  - C.A. Nichols, 1880-1900 J.R. Nisbet, 1853-1854 Hannah Norris, 1870-1873 J.F. Norris, 1866-1884 S.M. Osgood, 1834-1849 John Packer, 1872-1875. (Reel FM-28)
  - John Packer, 1876-1900 Frances Palmer, 1894 Emily Payne, 1877-1898 Lyman Peabody, 1895-1897 Frank Phinney, 1882-1891. (Reel FM-29)
  - Frank Phinney, 1892-1899 Jonathan Price, 1921-1829, journals W.I. Price, 1880-1887, 1892-1899 Carrie Putnam, 1894-1899 C.F. Raine, 1893-1895 Cornelia Rand, 1875-1878 S.B. Rand, 1870-1876 (Reel FM-30)
  - J. Harvey Randall, 1897-1900 Ruth Ranney, 1893-1899 Thomas ranney, 1844-1861 Miss S.E. Rathbun, 1879-1881 Merritt Richmond, 1886 E.B. Roach, 1887-1900 W.H. Roberts, 1878-1885 (Reel FM-31)
  - W.H. Roberts, 1886-1900 A.T. Rose, 1853-1885, 1891-1900 Alfred Satterlee, 1854-1856 A.E. Seagrave, 1890-1900 W.A. Sharp, 1893-1897. (Reel FM-32)
  - W.A. Sharp, 1898-1900 Miss M. Sheldon, 1877-1895 Elma Simons, 1892-1900 Thomas Simons, 1831-1875 Sarah Slater, 1892-1900 William Sloan, 1875-1878 D.A.W. Smith, 1864-1876. (Reel FM-33)
  - D.A.W. Smith, 1877-1900 David Smith, 1885-1888 Jesse Smith, 1898-1900 Eva Stark, 1891-1892 Edward Stevens, 1838-1857. (Reel FM-34)
  - Edward Stevens, 1858-1896 Edward O. Stevens, 1865-1876. (Reel FM-35)
  - Edward O. Stevens, 1877-1886, 1892-1899 Lyman Stilson, 1838-1859 F.P. Sutherland, 1892-1900 Ella Taylor, 1892-1897 Benjamin Thomas, 1851-1857. (Reel FM-36)
  - Benjamin Thomas, 1858-1868 Mrs. Benjamin Thomas, 1874-1893 W.F. Thomas, 1881-1892. (Reel FM-37)
  - W.F. Thomas, 1893-1900 Thora Thompson, 1897-1900 H.H. Tilbe, 1892-1900 E. Tribolet, 1892-1900 W.O. Valentine, 1895-1899 H.L. Van Meter, 1849-1865. (Reel FM-38)
  - H.L. Van Meter, 1866-1871 Mary Van Meter, 1881 Herbert Vinton, 1894-1900 Justus B. Vinton, 1871-1900 Justou H. Vinton, 1833-1860, deputation ? two folders (Reel FM-39)
  - Miranda Vinton, 1843-1856 Jonathan Wade, 1824-1834, record of the voyage of the ship Cashmere ? 1834, Letters ? 1835-1859. (Reel FM-40)
  - Jonathan Wade, 1860-1871 Mary Walling, 1875-1877 F.E. Warner, 1891 G.P. Watrous, 1854-1864 Helen Watson, 1874-1877 Isabella Watson, 1868-1900 Abner Webb, 1832-1838 David Webster, 1878-1884 David Whitaker, 1853-1858 F.T. Whitman, 1894-1895 Nanna Wilson, 1889 Miss H.E.T. Wright, 1850-1855 W.M. Young, 1891-1900. (Reel FM-41)
  - George Brock, 1898-1900 Edwin Bullard, 1870-1878, 1880-1900 John Burditt, 1881-1894 Ellen Bustard, 1896-1899 W.W. Campbell, 1874-1879 (Reel FM-43)
  - Policy, miscellany, 1800-1900 Policy re: colored missionaries, 1800-1900 Policy re: comity, 1800-1900 Policy re: formation of society, 1800-1900 Presbyterian Board, north, 1800-1900 Luther Rice, 1800-1900 John D. Rockefeller, 1800-1900 S, 1800-1900 Southern Baptist Board, 1800-1900 John Stevens, 1800-1900 James Sutherland, 1800-1900 T, 1800-1900 C.F. Tolman, 1800-1900 Jonah Warren, 1800-1900 Francis Wayland, 1882-1894 Francis Wayland, Sr., 1825 Jacob Weston, 1800-1900 Woman?s Society, 1870-1900. Assam: Miscellany, 1800-1900 Kandura, Gauhati, 1878-1887 (Reel FM-106)
  - Bengal: Orissa, miscellany, 1800-1900. Burman: J.S. Aaron (Mandalay), 1800-1900 Burmaa-English Baptist Church (Moulmein), 1800-1900 Burma-English Baptist Church (Rangoon), 1800-1900 Burma-Telegu and Tamie Baptist Church (Rangoon), 1800-1900 Miscellany, 1800-1900. China: Miscellany, 1800-1900. England: Miscellany, 1800-1900 H. Grattan Guiness (London), 1883-1900 Joseph Symm (London), 1800-1900. India: Miscellany, 1800-1900 William Carey English Baptist Mission (Calcutta), 1800-1900 South India English Baptist Church (Madras), 1800-1900 Ongole High School and College Inquirey, 1800-1900 William Pearce (Calcutta), 1825-1838. Japan: Miscellany, 1800-1900 J.W. Roberts, 1800-1900 George Stone, 1896-1900. South India: William Taylor, 1900 (Reel FM-107)
  - Samuel Smith, 1860-1897 Robert Telford, 1853-1864. Judson Correspondence Adoniram Judson to Board, 1810-1849 (Reel FM-111)
  - "Lord?s Prayer" versified ? Prison, Ava, 1825 Journals, 1827-1834 Anna Judson, "Vindication of Mrs. Judson" circular, 1823 Judson?s letter on dress - pamphlet ? Moulmein, 1831 Letters to friends Letter to "Mrs. Chaplin" (true copy), Rangoon, June 7, 1831 Letter to Pearce, Calcutta, re: Burmese type ordered, 1827 Correspondence with Knowles and Pattisen re: Mission to Palestine, 1832 Letter to the Bible class in the Pine Street Sabbath School, April 11, 1847 Letter to L. Stilson, 1847 Letter from the Board ? T.S. Malcolm, 1848-1850 Letter to Mrs. Bennett ? sympathy of parting from her husband, 1833 Correspondence with Aboner P. Webb, enc. Plan for Burmese in Roman script, 1834 Correspondence with Howard Malcolm, 1837 Letters to Wayland, 1826-1838 Letters from missionaries Letters to Judson from friends Address to Females in America by Ann H. Judson Letters to Judson from Board ? L. Boles ? 1826-1832 Letters to Judson from Board ? S. Peck Letters to Judson from Board- Letters to Judson from Board ? H. Lincoln ? 1847-1849 Letters to Judson from Board ? R.E. Eddy ? 1848-1849 Letters to Judson from Board ? Edward Bright, 1850 Letters from sister Abigail Judson Letters to Judson from O.T. Cutter Letters from Lewis Colley re: memoir, Sarah B. Judson Judson autograph given to Robert Fuller Letters from Religious Tract Society of London Ann H. Judson Letters from Sarah Judson to parents and friends, to Dr. and Mrs. Bolles, to Mrs. Mason, 1834-1844 Abby Ann Judson (daughter), 1845-1849. (Reel FM-112)
  - Abby Ann Judson (daughter), 1851-1854 Adoniram Brown Judson (son) Edward Judson (son) Elnathan Judson (son) Henry Judson (son) George Dana Boardman, Jr. (son) letters from Emily Judson to the board Letters to Emily Judson from friends, A ? H. (Reel FM-113)
  - Letters to Emily Judson from friends, I ? Z Letters to Adoniram Judson from W.D. Ticknor Co. re: Alderbrookk Correspondence for Judson relatives, 1800-1900 A. Emily Chubbuck. (Reel FM-114)
  - Letters to Emily Chubbuck from friends. (Reel FM-115)
- Series II. Subject file--Burma
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? Burma Bible & Tract Soc. 1876-1895 (Reel 700-4-2)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? Rangoon Missy. Soc. 1865-1884 (Reel 700-4-1)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? Minutes of Burma Missy. Conference 1810/15/21/65 (Reel 700-3-3)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? Mission problems related to Rangoon property & McVinton 1885-1923 (Reel 700-3-2)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? Maulmain Baptist Missionary Soc. 1838, 1840, 1841, 1844, 1845, 1847, 1849, 1852, 1853 (Reel 700-3-1)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? Minutes of Missionaries? meetings of Burma Mission in Moulmein - 1831 (Reel 700-2-3)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? Sesquicentennial Pageant on Baptist work in Burma. E. & G. Sowards & R. Gilson. 1813-1963 (Reel 700-2-2)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? Missions in Burma ABMU 1813-1919 (Reel 700-2-1)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? General Information (Reel 700-1-23)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? Literature Lists (Reel 700-1-22)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? Christian women in Burma (Reel 700-1-21)
  - Burma-Old Burma - Nationals (Reel 700-1-20)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? The Maritime Provinces (Reel 700-1-19)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? Pre-War Clippings (Reel 700-1-18)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? General Government booklet on seeds & plants 1938 (Reel 700-1-17)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? The Campbell Report - 1936 (Reel 700-1-16)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? "Old Rangoon" Burma Research Society, 1935 (Reel 700-1-15)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? Archaeological notes on Mandalay, 1931 (Reel 700-1-14)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? European writers on Burma Rangoon Gazette 2/1/1926 (Reel 700-1-13)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? Namtu, Burma?s Industrial Wonderland ? Rangoon Gazette 4/30/1923 (Reel 700-1-12)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? Literacy ? Census 1923 (Reel 700-1-11)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? Census ? Christianity in Burma 1921 and 1933 (Reel 700-1-10)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? "A Burmas Princess" the Story of Daw Pwa Kin 1916 (Reel 700-1-9)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? Building an American Bridge in Burma ? World?s work 9.1901 (Reel 700-1-8)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? Catholicism 1900 (Reel 700-1-7)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? Maymyo ? Directions for Grant of Land for building and other purposes - 1897 (Reel 700-1-6)
  - Burma-Old Burma ?"The Races of Burma" by E.F. Merriam - 1893 (Reel 700-1-5)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? Notes on a decade in Burma 1889-1899 (Reel 700-1-4)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? "Rangoon Fifty years ago" C. Bennett 1884 (Reel 700-1-3)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? Burma Census, 1881-1931 (Reel 700-1-2)
  - Burma-Old Burma ? Tenasserim Provinces ? Statistics and Government Calcutta Review 1847 (Reel 700-1-1)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? Five visits to the Burma Mission House - 1887 (Reel 701-2-1)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission - Glimpses of Mission work in Burma. Susan Haswell, 1893 (Reel 701-2-2)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? Bassein. The Teachers and Pupils of the Amer. Bapt. Mission Schools, 1901 (Reel 701-2-3)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? The American Baptist Mission in Burma. Armstrong, 1901 (Reel 701-2-4)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? Shirk Memorial Rest House, Maymo, 1908-1912 (Reel 701-2-5)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? The Judson Centennial. Rangoon Gazette 12/1913 (Reel 701-2-6)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? Gallery of Statistical Photographs American Baptist Mission, 1920-1934 (Reel 701-2-7)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? Christian Progress in Burma 1927 (Reel 701-2-8)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? Christian Missions in Burma A survey by C.E. Olmstead. Burma Christian Council 1927 (Reel 701-2-9)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? The Gospel Teams, 1928-1931 (Reel 701-3-1)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? American Baptist Mission Publicity leaflets - 1937 (Reel 701-3-2)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? Racial groups ? Distribution of principal races, 1939 (Reel 701-3-3)
  - Bitma-American Baptist Mission ? The mission manual ? Compiled by the Mission attorney, 1941 (Reel 701-3-4)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? Christian progress to the invasion World Dominion press 1942 (Reel 701-3-5)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? General Information (Reel 701-3-6)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? Rangoon, Mission Guest House Ahlone (Reel 701-3-7)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? "Literature in Burma" A.C. Hanna, 1920?s (Reel 701-3-8)
  - Burma-American Baptist Mission ? Rangoon YMCA (Reel 701-3-9)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports ? Reports for 1911 (Reel 701-4-1)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports ? Reports for 1913 (Reel 701-4-2)
  - Burma Mission Secretaries Annual Reports. Kachins-Burma Mission Secretary?s Report 1920-1934 (Reel 701-4-3)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports ? Report of the field Secretary ABFMS - 1921 (Reel 701-4-4)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports ? Report of the Field Secretary ABFMS - 1922 (Reel 701-4-5)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports, Report of the Field Secretary ABFMS 1923 (Reel 701-5-1)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports ? Report for 1924 Soul Winners in Burma, 1924 (Reel 701-5-2)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports ? Report of the Field Secretary ? ABFMS, 1924-1925 (Reel 701-5-3)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports ? Report of the Field secretary ABFMS, 1927 (Reel 702-1-1)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports ? Report of the Field Secretary ABFMS 1928 (Reel 702-1-2)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports ? Report of the Fiels Secretary ABFMS 1929 (Reel 702-1-3)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports ? Report of the Field Secretary ABFMS 1930 (Reel 702-1-4)
  - Burma-MissionSecretaries Annual Reports ? Report of the Field Secretary ABFMS 1931 (Reel 702-1-5)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports ? Report of the Field Secretary ABFMS 1932 (Reel 702-1-6)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports ? Report on Christian Education in Burma. Dr. F.A. Padelford, 1832-1933 (Reel 702-2-2)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports ? Report of the Field Secretary, ABFMS 1933 (Reel 702-2-3)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Report ? Burma Evaluation Studies, 1933-1938 (Reel 702-2-4)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports ? Report of the Field Secretary ABFMS 1934 (Reel 702-2-5)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports ? Report of the Field Secretaru ABFMS 1935 (Reel 702-3-1)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports ? Report of the Field Secretary ABFMS 1936 (Reel 702-3-2)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports ? Report of the Field Secretary ? ABFMS 1937 (Reel 702-3-3)
  - Burma-Mission secretaries Annual Reports ? Report of the Field Secretary ? ABFMS 1938 (Reel 702-3-4)
  - Burma-Mission Secretaries Annual Reports ? Report of the Field Secretary ? ABFMS 1941-1942 (Reel 702-3-5)
  - Burma ? Administration ? Deputation to Burma Convention at Moulmein, April 4-May 7, 1853 (Reel 702-3-6)
  - Burma ? Administration "Baptist Episcopacy" ABMU & Missionaries Dispute 1858 (Reel 702-3-7)
  - Burma ? Administration "Self Support & Mission Policy" C.H. Carpenter ? A review by A. Bunker, 1885 (Reel 702-3-8)
  - Burma ? Administration ? The Burman Mission. E.F. Merriam, 1893 (Reel 702-3-9)
  - Burma ? Administration "Management of A.B. Mission in Burma" Controversy 1893-1894 (Reel 702-4-1)
  - Burma ? Administration ? Burma Baptist Missionary Conference Constitutions 1898-1937 (Reel 702-4-2)
  - Burma ? Administration ? Burma Baptist Missionary Conference Development of Field. C.E. Chaney. 1900-1925 (Reel 702-4-3)
  - Burma ? Administration ? Mission Administration in Burma 1914 (Reel 702-4-4)
  - Burma ? Administration ? Statistical interpretation 1920-1934 (Reel 702-4-5)
  - Burma ? Administration ? Relations with American Methodist 1922, 1923, 1931 (Reel 702-4-6)
  - Burma ? Administration ? Burma Bapt. Missionary Conference ? Policy Studies 1925-1931 (Reel 702-4-7)
  - Burma ? Administration ? Teacher training in Burma. H.E. Hinton 1927 (Reel 702-4-8)
  - Burma ? Administration ? Devolution 1927-1928 (Reel 702-4-9)
  - Burma ? Administration ? Burma Survey 1928-1929 (Reel 702-5-1)
  - Burma ? Administration ? Constitutions, Burmese & Karen Joint Committees 1929 (Reel 702-5-2)
  - Burma ? Administration ? Burma Mission Survey. Basis of Board of Education Studies 1933-1938. Volume 1 (Reel 702-5-3)
  - Burma ? Administration ? Burma Mission Survey. Basis of Board of Education Studies, 1933-1938 Volume II (Reel 703-1-1)
  - Burma ? Administration ? Burma Mission Survey. Basis of Board of Education Studies 1933-1938. Volume III (Reel 703-1-2)
  - Burma ? Administration ? An integrated program of Education G.D. Josif, 1935 (Reel 703-1-3)
  - Burma ? Administration ? Future policies for the Burma Mission C.E. Chaney, 1935 (Reel 703-1-4)
  - Burma ? Administration. Burma Baptist Mission Society Report 1935 (Reel 703-1-5)
  - Burma ? Administration. Evaluation Studies ? Replies from Burma 1936-37 (Reel 703-1-6)
  - Burma ? Administration. Burma Baptist Mission society Constitution 1938 (Reel 703-2-1)
  - Burma ? Comity ? Kentung ABMU & Presbyterians USA. Comity Agreement 1900-1918 (Reel 703-2-2)
  - Burma ? Comity ? Kentung Conference with Presbyterian Laos Mission Volume 1, 1906 (Reel 703-2-3)
  - Burma ? Comity ? Kentung Conf. With Pres. Laos Mission V.III 1907 (Reel 703-3-1)
  - Burma ? Comity ? Kentung Conf. With Pres. Laos Mission V.IV 1907 (Reel 703-3-2)
  - Burma ? Burma Baptist Convention. First Annual Report of the Burma Baptist Missionary Convention, Rangoon 10/28-11/2/1866 (Reel 703-3-3)
  - Burma ? Baptist Convention ? Reports 1921-1937 (Reel 703-3-4)
  - Burma ? Burma Baptist Convention, Board of Publication Accounts, 1959-1961 (Reel 703-3-5)
  - Burma ? Daily Vacation Bible School, General Material 1928-1941 (Reel 703-4-1)
  - Burma ? Asho Chin ? Sandoway, 1915-1936 (Reel 703-4-2)
  - Burma ? Asho Chin ? Thayetmyo, 1936 (Reel 703-4-3)
  - Burma ? Asho Chin ? The First Arakanese Christian. 1938 (Reel 703-4-4)
  - Burma ? Burmese-Burman Women?s Missionary Society, 1923-1940 (Reel 703-4-5)
  - Burma ? Burmese-Bassein, 1923-1941 (Reel 703-4-6)
  - Burma ? Burmese-Henzada, 1925-1939 (Reel 703-4-7)
  - Burma ? Burmese-Mandaley, 1886-1937 (Reel 703-4-8)
  - Burma ? Burmese Moulmein, 1929 (Reel 703-4-9)
  - Burma ? Burmese-Pegu, 1925-1941 (Reel 703-4-11)
  - Burma ? Burmese-Prome, 1909-1941 (Reel 703-4-12)
  - Burma ? Burmese-Myinayan, 1925 (Reel 703-4-10)
  - Burma ? Burmese-Prome History of Prome Church, R. Seagrave, 1941 (Reel 703-4-13)
  - Burma ? Burmese-Pyapon, 1924-1934 (Reel 703-4-14)
  - Burma ? Burmese-Pyinmana, 1904 (Reel 703-4-15)
  - Burma ? Burmese-Sagaing, 1925-1935 (Reel 703-5-1)
  - Burma ? Burmese-Taunggui, 1927-1932 (Reel 703-5-2)
  - Burma ? Burmese-Tavoy, 1926-1940 (Reel 703-5-3)
  - Burma ? Burmese-Thonze, Zigon, 1924-1941 (Reel 704-1-1)
  - Burma ? Chin-Chins, 1888-1934 (Reel 704-1-2)
  - Burma ? Chin-Total Abstinence Issue, 1932 (Reel 704-1-3)
  - Burma ? Chins-General Material, 1935-1942 (Reel 704-1-4)
  - Burma ? English and Anglo/Indian-English Baptist Church, Rangoon United with Immanuel Bapt. Ch. 1883-1895 (Reel 704-1-5)
  - Burma ? English & Anglo/Indian-English Baptist Church, Rangoon Court Casr 1885-1897 (Reel 704-1-6)
  - Burma ? English & Anglo/Indian English Baptist Church, Periodical "Ensign" 1895-1896 (Reel 704-2-1)
  - Burma ? English & Anglo/Indian-English Baptist Church, Rangoon, 1896 (Reel 704-3-1)
  - Burma ? English & Anglo/Indian-Immanuel Baptist Ch. Rangoon, History 1896-1935 (Reel 704-3-2)
  - Burma ? English & Anglo/Indian ? Moulmein: English Bapt. Ch. History (Reel 704-3-3)
  - Burma ? English & Anglo/Indian-English work for Anglo Indians Study 1916 (Reel 704-4-1)
  - Burma ? Indian ? Moulmein, 1904 and 1933 (Reel 704-4-2)
  - Burma ? Indian ? Union Hall School, Rangoon 1905-1951 (Reel 704-4-3)
  - Burma ? Indian Myers-Duff Controversy, 1920 (Reel 704-4-4)
  - Burma ? Indian ? The Indian problem in Burma 9/8/24 (Reel 704-4-5)
  - Burma ? Kachin ? Notes on Early Kachin work (Reel 704-4-6)
  - Burma ? Kachin ? Old Correspondence, 1883 and 1922, 1924 (Reel 704-4-7)
  - Burma ? Kachin ? Bhamo destruction, 1884 (Reel 704-4-8)
  - Burma ? Sgaw Karen ? Thattawaddy, 1923-1941 (Reel 704-4-9)
  - Burma ? Sgaw Karen ? High School, Rangoon & Nichols Sgaw Karen High School, 1925-1940 (Reel 704-4-10)
  - Burma ? Sgaw Karen ? Henzada, 1927-1932 (Reel 704-4-11)
  - Burma ? Sgaw Karen ? Moulmein, 1927-1940 (Reel 704-4-12)
  - Burma-Pwo Karen General, 1922-1941 (Reel 704-4-13)